```json
{
  "tests": [
    {
      "id": "staar_reading_7_2018",
      "subject": "Reading",
      "grade": "7",
      "year": "2018",
      "defaultQuestionType": "multiple-choice",
      "passages": [
        {
          "passageId": "p1",
          "title": "Vacation Exaggeration",
          "content": "When I complained to Mom over the phone yesterday about the extreme depths of boredom I had experienced during the first week of my summer exile to my grandparents' farm, she suggested I think of my grandparents' farm as an exotic location. \"After all,\" she said, \"not everyone gets the opportunity to live on a farm.\"\n\nThat gave me an idea. I decided I would compose my social media status updates as if I were an illustrious traveler visiting the Serengeti Plain and making keen observations to my fans about my surroundings. I started early the next morning.\n\n*Alyssa's Status:* 5:54 A.M. The glorious male *Gallus gallus domesticus*, more commonly known as the rooster, perches himself upon the post. His delicate feathers glimmer in the sunrise. He flaps his wings twice and rears back his head. His call clamors through the countryside, crying out to all creatures that morning has come.\n\n14 Thumbs Up\n\nTo add to my suffering, my best friends were each doing something exciting. Carlos was at the beach rescuing sea turtles, and Natalia was with her mother, who is an interior designer working on a project for a famous client in a big city.\n\nBut several people had given a thumbs-up to my post, and it was getting almost the same amount of attention as my friends' posts.\n\n*Carlos's Status:* 7:39 A.M. I'm about to search for sea turtle nests on my section of the beach. I hope I find one today!\n\n21 Thumbs Up\n\n*Natalia's Status:* 11:19 A.M. Which do you think would be a better color to paint rock star Aaron Slayton's loft apartment: Electric Eclectic Orange or Superfly Lemon Lime?\n\n28 Thumbs Up\n\nAs I was thinking of a comment to post on Natalia's page, Grandma interrupted me.\n\n\"Put your shoes on, Alyssa. We're heading to Haverford's farm.\"\n\n\"Why?\"\n\n\"It's a summer tradition. On the first Saturday of July, the whole town goes to Mr. Haverford's place to pick blackberries. If we pick enough, we can make a blackberry cobbler tonight.\"\n\nInteresting. I typed my next update.\n\nAlyssa's Status: 1:34 P.M. Few events cause more excitement in this remote part of the world than the ripening of the blackberries, a cause for celebration among the local inhabitants who make the annual pilgrimage to a special place known as \"Haverford's.\" After the festivities have concluded, a ceremonial cobbler—a sweet dessert—is baked with the ripest of the day's bounty.\n\n18 Thumbs Up\n\nBoth Carlos and Natalia replied to my post.\n\nCarlos's Reply: 1:39 P.M. Mmm! I love blackberry cobbler! I've never made it from scratch with freshly picked berries before. Have some for me!\n\nNatalia's Reply: 1:46 P.M. I can't believe you're staying at a farm! I like the city, but it's so crowded. I could use some open space and fresh air.\n\nLater that evening, after I had eaten two servings of cobbler, I uploaded photos of the sprawling acreage of Haverford's farm and described in vivid detail the flavors and textures of the dessert.\n\nThe next morning I traipsed to the kitchen, where Grandma was busy making breakfast. She smiled when she saw me.\n\n\"Good morning, Alyssa,\" Grandma said as she handed me a glass of freshly squeezed orange juice. \"You know, I was just thinking that today might be a good day for you to explore the old barn.\"\n\nThat had potential for a worthy photo to post online. I could take a picture of the run-down barn and make up a story—maybe an unsolved mystery. I could tweak the brightness and contrast settings of the photograph, slightly changing them to make the picture look eerie.\n\nWhile I was planning this post, Grandma set a heaping plate of pancakes in front of me. Obviously, I had to post about the perks of having Grandma's home cooking.\n\nAfter breakfast I went to the barn. I took out my phone so that I could use it as a flashlight. I heaved the door open and peered inside. Everything was covered in dirt and cobwebs. Perfect!\n\nThen I heard a whining sound from a corner of the barn and almost vaulted to the ceiling.\n\nI gathered myself and went toward the sound. When I saw what was in one of the stalls, I let out a high-pitched squeal—baby foxes! They were crawling out of a hole and then tumbling back down. They were adorable. I probably took a hundred photos.\n\n\"Fox kits,\" Grandma said later when she saw the photographs I had taken. \"I've seen a fox around and wondered if she had a den. You should put one of these on your social studies page.\"\n\n\"Social media, Grandma,\" I said, correcting her. \"And that's a great idea. Everyone loves cute animals.\"\n\nAlyssa's Status: 4:47 P.M. Look who decided to make my grandparents' barn their new home!\n\nWithin a few minutes I had received several comments from my friends and a thumbs-up from 25 people.\n\nNatalia's Reply: 5:05 P.M. So cute! The only animals in the city are giant rats and pigeons.\n\nCarlos's Reply: 5:12 P.M. Wow! Take lots of pictures. They look as though they're almost old enough to leave their den.\n\nI reread the comments. Carlos and Natalia thought my farm adventures were interesting, and Natalia's reply even had a tinge of jealousy.\n\n\"What are you smiling about?\" Grandma asked.\n\n\"I—\"\n\nI was going to say that I was thrilled with all the attention my post had received, but as the words formed in my brain, I looked at Grandma smiling back at me.\n\n\"I'm really glad I'm getting to spend some time at your farm this summer,\" I said. And I meant it."
        },
        {
          "passageId": "p2",
          "title": "Quite an Achievement!",
          "content": "On a hot, sunny afternoon in Tempe, Arizona, a construction manager instructs a work crew to begin installing a set of solar panels at a local business. In Milwaukee, Wisconsin, a banker chooses a new house with the help of a real estate agent. In Wilmington, Delaware, people crowd into a seminar designed to help them understand how to save for a new car. These activities all seem rather ordinary until you look more closely. All the people involved are under the age of 14. They and thousands like them are participating in an organization called Junior Achievement (JA).\n\nFounded in 1919, Junior Achievement works with more than 9 million young people around the world, helping them \"dream big\" and teaching them the skills they need to be successful businesspeople, effective money managers, and productive members of their community. The program is run largely by volunteers from area businesses and universities, parents, and senior citizens—all of whom believe in the potential of young people.\n\nIn the program students in fourth through sixth grade become citizens of JA BizTown, where they learn how to run a city. Students use a portion of their school day to learn about business strategies and the roles of workers and city leaders. Then they create and oversee the management of a simulated city made up of a bank, businesses, restaurants, and retail stores. It is not unusual to see a BizTown student wearing a hard hat and learning about construction or interviewing for a job with actual business owners. BizTown students become managers, clerks, and customers. They even pay taxes and elect their own mayor. They also make their own laws and must abide by them or else pay fines. These students don't just learn about how a town works—they make real-life decisions that affect what goes on in their town. Pershing Elementary School teacher Luz Pineda is an advocate of BizTown. \"This program prepares children for the future,\" she said. \"This shows them what will really happen when they're adults.\"\n\nJunior Achievement also provides middle and high school students with a challenging program called JA Finance Park. Each student is assigned an age, a job, a salary, and a family. They must create a personal budget and plan a career that will help them meet their goals and live within their budget. JoAnn Goldberger, senior director of strategic partnerships for Junior Achievement of Central Maryland, states, \"We teach them how to save for the future on whatever budget they have. Maybe they can't afford that mansion with a pool. Maybe a sports car isn't really feasible when you have three kids. Not everybody can be Justin Bieber.\" Finance Park is designed to ensure the real-world experience is real indeed. An \"unlucky chance card\" can assign a student a flat tire or a broken air conditioner, training them to plan for and solve the kinds of problems their parents encounter every day.\n\nBy taking part in Junior Achievement, students learn not only the importance of choosing a career and managing their finances but also the skills needed in order to be successful in doing so. Junior Achievement teaches students skills and concepts such as preparing for a job interview, understanding how officials are elected, analyzing the steps to opening a business, and paying taxes. It also allows students to experience the value of giving through volunteer work and community service.\n\nThe concepts taught in BizTown and Finance Park have proved so popular that they are now being included in Scouting programs, preschools, and summer camps. Partnering with Junior Achievement, both Girl Scouts and Boy Scouts now offer badges for learning money management and investment skills. Suzanne Harper, national program director of the Girl Scouts, is pleased that even kindergarten-aged Scouts can learn how to earn money. Imagine children learning to buy and trade stocks at a Scout meeting! Finance is not just for grade-school students and teens, either. The financial literacy encouraged by Junior Achievement has even inspired other programs to offer similar resources. In San Francisco a new library opened recently with a preschool program that offers books about money management for children as young as three years old. This program is praised by people like Lori Mackey, founder of a financial literacy website for children. Mackey strongly believes that financial skills are as critical as basic reading skills for young children.\n\nEven summer camp is not just about swimming and crafts anymore. BizTown operates a nationwide summer camp where students ages 10 to 14 come from across the country to work together and, along with their teachers, create and manage a simulated economy. For those who can't attend the camp, many communities offer free local summer camps that teach the same skills.\n\nGrowing up and entering the \"real world\" is a challenge everyone must face. Thanks to Junior Achievement, students can be prepared. By practicing financial skills and learning good community habits, students in Junior Achievement gain valuable experience that will last a lifetime."
        },
        {
          "passageId": "p3",
          "title": "Natural Inspiration",
          "content": "Many inventors spend years thinking about and developing their ideas before their inventions become reality. Sometimes, though, a person unexpectedly stumbles across the perfect idea, as did the Swiss engineer George de Mestral.\n\nMestral was born in 1907 and became interested in building and design when he was a child. As an adult he worked for an engineering company. In 1941, Mestral was outside with his dog when he noticed small, round seedpods stuck to his clothing and his dog's fur. As he was removing these pesky burrs, he began wondering how the seedpods attached themselves to different materials.\n\nWanting to learn the answer, Mestral took a look at the burrs under a microscope. What he saw was that the prickly stickers on the burrs had hooks. It was these tiny hooks that allowed the burrs to latch onto the soft loops in the fabric of his clothing and in his dog's fur. Mestral realized he could create something similar that could be used as a fastener. He began to call his idea \"velcro\"—a combination of the words \"velvet\" and \"crochet.\" Velcro also became the name of the company that manufactures the fastener.\n\nWhen Mestral first presented his idea to manufacturing companies, the companies were not interested. After several rejections, he enlisted the help of sewing experts in France to develop his idea. At first Mestral used cotton for his two-sided fasteners, but repeated fastening and unfastening caused the cotton to wear too quickly. He eventually began using the synthetic material nylon, which was sturdier. It took Mestral nearly 10 years to perfect his design and automated production methods. The invention was patented in Switzerland in 1955.\n\nVelcro began to sell very well and became known as the \"zipperless zipper.\" In the 1960s the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) began using Velcro to secure equipment in the zero-gravity environment of outer space. Velcro was also used to fasten devices in hospitals, hold together car parts, and make the seats of airplanes detachable. In 1968, Velcro made its first appearance on footwear, and soon children around the world were fastening their shoes with Velcro instead of shoelaces.\n\nToday the Velcro company is worth millions of dollars because so many people have recognized the variety of uses for the hook-and-loop fastener. Just as Mestral was inspired by nature to create his invention, people continue to be inspired to find new uses for Velcro."
        },
        {
          "passageId": "p4",
          "title": "A Brilliant Beetle",
          "content": "Natural resources are materials or substances that occur in nature and are of some value to humans. Depending on the environment, certain natural resources are more scarce than others and therefore more valuable. More than one billion people currently live in environments where water is in short supply, making water one of the most highly prized natural resources on the planet. Scientists are always searching for ways to increase access to this valuable resource. They may have found a solution in an unlikely area: one of the most arid places on Earth.\n\nDespite being one of the world's driest places, with only several inches of annual rainfall, the Namib desert in Africa is home to many creatures. The Namib beetle is a unique organism that thrives in this environment because of its amazing physical adaptation. The wings on the Namib beetle are filled with bumps and grooves that help it collect water from the air. The top of each bump is smooth like glass and attracts water. But the slopes of each bump and the troughs in between the bumps have waxy surfaces that repel water.\n\nThe design of the Namib beetle's wings allows the beetle to harvest water in an environment where there is virtually none. The beetle takes advantage of the fog that rolls into the Namib desert about six times a month. Each time this occurs, the Namib beetle positions its body at a 45-degree angle to the wind. As the wind pushes the fog across the desert, each bump on the beetle's back collects tiny droplets of water. When enough moisture has been collected from the fog, a drop rolls off the bumps into the waxy grooves and then into the mouth of the beetle.\n\nScientists are using the Namib beetle's wing design as a guide for creating their own water-collection surfaces. Scientists working at a laboratory for the British Ministry of Defence have embedded dozens of glass spheres into thin layers of wax. Similar to the bumps and grooves on the wings of the beetle, the smooth glass bubbles collect water, while the wax repels it. By placing the glass-and-wax panels in environments with high-moisture air, the scientists think they will be able to collect water. The scientists hope the beetle-inspired panels can increase people's access to water in areas where water is scarce.\n\nThe Namib beetle's extraordinary wing design may also provide unexpected solutions to other modern-day problems. In areas where dense fog causes disruptions, panels of these water-gathering surfaces may be able to eliminate the fog. This could potentially reduce travel delays at airports and prevent fog-related hazards on roadways. It seems that studying this little beetle may lead to a variety of benefits for humans."
        },
        {
          "passageId": "p5_paired",
          "title": "Paired Passages: Natural Inspiration & A Brilliant Beetle",
          "content": "[This is a paired passage entry. The content is drawn from p3 and p4.]"
        },
        {
          "passageId": "p6",
          "title": "My River",
          "content": "My river has a bridge where I like to sit, dangling my legs, and listen.\n\nLots of things change quickly, but the river takes its time. And for some reason that's comforting.\n\nThe summer-green grass whispers excitedly as if passing on secrets. The trees murmur wisely, nodding with the wind.\n\nThe birds gossip, and there are rustles and an occasional splash as various animals go about living.\n\nAnd then there is the river, which passes on heedless of all, intent always to push forward.\n\nAs it flows beneath me it seems to say hello and goodbye at once— \"Must be moving, there is so much to see!\" It reminds me that life is an adventure.\n\nAnd whatever bad feelings I brought with me, the river carries them away.\n\nRivers make good friends. They help you remember what the world makes you forget."
        },
        {
          "passageId": "p7",
          "title": "\"Carry Him Everywhere You Go\"",
          "content": "The best advice I received about raising a puppy didn't come from a book or a class but over the phone from a gritty voice with a southern twang. Paige Foster, Atticus's breeder, suggested I carry him with me everywhere we went during the first month we were together. I stretched it to two.\n\n\"And don't let anyone else hold him during that time,\" she added. \"He needs to know you're his family. Y'all will bond that way.\"\n\nI owe much to Paige. Buying a puppy from her meant having the freedom to pick her brain, no matter how often I called—calls that in the beginning were more frequent than she bargained for, I'm sure, and were typically panic-driven. I liked her style. During our conversations, which were always lengthy, I came to think of her as intuitive, and I trusted her in every way. By following Paige's advice, Atticus and I were able to forgo obedience school, much to the chagrin of various self-proclaimed dog experts we met through the years.\n\nOnce, upon seeing Atticus sitting up next to me on a park bench without a leash or collar on, one such expert marveled at how well behaved he was. She had a stern voice that made me feel as if I should be sitting up straight, too. She asked what kind of training I put him through, listing various intimidating words and phrases that sounded to my ear to be Germanic in root and I took to be the schools of thought for serious dog trainers.\n\nI shrugged. \"None, really. We just hang out together.\"\n\nThis did not sit well with her. She sized me up as a rube and gave me a look that fell halfway between pity and a scold before marching off in search, I imagined, of a music store where she could purchase some Wagner.\n\nFor as long as I can remember, people have commented on Atticus's peaceful demeanor. Then, as was almost always the case, they'd ask him to give them his paw. He wouldn't. Instead he just looked at them, not even bothering to cock his head.\n\nThey'd ask again. Again he just studied them.\n\nThen it typically went this way:\n\n\"Does he know how to give his paw?\"\n\n\"I don't know, never asked him.\"\n\n\"But didn't you teach him that?\"\n\n\"No. I didn't teach him anything.\"\n\nI never saw the point in teaching Atticus tricks. What I wanted from him was for him to be his own dog as much as I was my own man. The things I wanted him to learn were basic things that made going through life safe and easy. I know many who tell me that by teaching their dog tricks they worked on their relationship together. The dogs, I was told, liked the task and then the reward. I can't argue against any of that, but it wasn't for us.\n\nAll I wanted was for Atticus to fit in as much as he needed to so he wouldn't be a bother or get into trouble, but I also didn't think it was up to me to decide what he would become. That was up to him. As long as he could walk with me off leash, feel comfortable in public settings, and understand that he should never feel self-conscious anywhere, I was fine with it.\n\nMy carrying the little puppy in the length of my arm from wrist to elbow for two months, like a running back with a football, went a long way toward forging our relationship and deciding how things would be for years to come."
        }
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "questionId": "q1",
          "passageId": "p1",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The word illustrious in paragraph 2 means —",
          "options": [
            "lonely",
            "native",
            "famous",
            "inexperienced"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "famous"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q2",
          "passageId": "p1",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which phrase from paragraph 1 best demonstrates Alyssa's attitude about spending time at her grandparents' farm?",
          "options": [
            "over the phone yesterday",
            "week of my summer exile",
            "as an exotic location",
            "not everyone gets the opportunity"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "week of my summer exile"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q3",
          "passageId": "p1",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Read this sentence from paragraph 3.\n\nHis call clamors through the countryside, crying out to all creatures that morning has come.\n\nThe descriptive language in this sentence —",
          "options": [
            "gives Alyssa's post a dramatic effect",
            "shows how Alyssa's attitude has changed throughout the story",
            "mimics the sound of the rooster's call",
            "emphasizes that hearing the rooster is an important event in the plot"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "gives Alyssa's post a dramatic effect"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q4",
          "passageId": "p1",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The primary theme of the story centers on the importance of —",
          "options": [
            "telling the truth",
            "valuing friendship",
            "recognizing the beauty of nature",
            "appreciating current circumstances"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "appreciating current circumstances"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q5",
          "passageId": "p1",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Read paragraph 23 from the story.\n\nThen I heard a whining sound from a corner of the barn and almost vaulted to the ceiling.\n\nThe author includes the figurative language in this sentence to show that Alyssa —",
          "options": [
            "feels excited about her discovery",
            "is startled by the unexpected noise",
            "has a sudden inspiration for an online post",
            "thinks she should not be in the barn"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "is startled by the unexpected noise"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q6",
          "passageId": "p1",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "How does the story's setting influence its plot?",
          "options": [
            "Being far from her friends makes Alyssa feel isolated.",
            "Alyssa's separation from her mother helps her value her family more.",
            "The observations Alyssa makes at the farm give her something to write about.",
            "Alyssa's presence on the farm creates conflict with her grandmother."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The observations Alyssa makes at the farm give her something to write about."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q7",
          "passageId": "p1",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "At the end of the story, Alyssa most likely feels —",
          "options": [
            "sad because she knows she will have to leave the farm soon",
            "satisfied that her friends like her posts",
            "hopeful that she will enjoy the rest of her summer",
            "content because she realizes she likes being on the farm"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "content because she realizes she likes being on the farm"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q8",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The Latin root vocare, meaning \"to call,\" helps the reader understand that the word advocate in paragraph 3 means one who —",
          "options": [
            "studies other people",
            "provides support",
            "controls a group of people",
            "offers motivation"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "provides support"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q9",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The author includes quotations in paragraphs 3 and 4 in order to —",
          "options": [
            "recognize the contributions volunteers have made to Junior Achievement",
            "demonstrate that many adults support the work Junior Achievement does",
            "show that successful adults participated in Junior Achievement as students",
            "inspire students to become involved with Junior Achievement"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "demonstrate that many adults support the work Junior Achievement does"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q10",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "How does paragraph 5 help inform the reader about Junior Achievement?",
          "options": [
            "By summarizing the benefits of participating in Junior Achievement",
            "By emphasizing the changes Junior Achievement has made in order to meet the demands of modern life",
            "By explaining how community members assist in organizing Junior Achievement programs",
            "By showing how important it is for teachers to motivate students to participate in Junior Achievement programs"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "By summarizing the benefits of participating in Junior Achievement"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q11",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which sentence suggests that Junior Achievement students will be well prepared to join the working world?",
          "options": [
            "In San Francisco a new library opened recently with a preschool program that offers books about money management for children as young as three years old.",
            "Growing up and entering the \"real world\" is a challenge everyone must face.",
            "It is not unusual to see a BizTown student wearing a hard hat and learning about construction or interviewing for a job with actual business owners.",
            "The program is run largely by volunteers from area businesses and universities, parents, and senior citizens—all of whom believe in the potential of young people."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "It is not unusual to see a BizTown student wearing a hard hat and learning about construction or interviewing for a job with actual business owners."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q12",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The author organizes the selection by —",
          "options": [
            "comparing Junior Achievement's benefits with those gained by Scouting or attending summer camp",
            "explaining what Junior Achievement does by giving in-depth examples of its programs",
            "detailing how volunteers contribute to Junior Achievement's overall goal",
            "describing how Junior Achievement has changed since it first started offering programs"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "explaining what Junior Achievement does by giving in-depth examples of its programs"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q13",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The reader can conclude that Junior Achievement, Girl Scouts, and Boy Scouts all share which belief?",
          "options": [
            "Every child should have the opportunity to attend summer camp.",
            "Students of all ages are capable of owning their own businesses.",
            "Many people buy more things than they can afford.",
            "Managing a personal budget is a necessary skill."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Managing a personal budget is a necessary skill."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q14",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The main goal of Junior Achievement is to —",
          "options": [
            "involve students in their local city government",
            "help students earn money while attending school",
            "allow students to improve businesses in their community",
            "prepare students for adult responsibilities"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "prepare students for adult responsibilities"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q15",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "In which sentence does the author make a factual claim?",
          "options": [
            "Imagine children learning to buy and trade stocks at a Scout meeting!",
            "Even summer camp is not just about swimming and crafts anymore.",
            "The concepts taught in BizTown and Finance Park have proved so popular that they are now being included in Scouting programs, preschools, and summer camps.",
            "These activities all seem rather ordinary until you look more closely."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The concepts taught in BizTown and Finance Park have proved so popular that they are now being included in Scouting programs, preschools, and summer camps."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q16",
          "passageId": "p2",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which idea in the selection do the photographs support?",
          "options": [
            "Junior Achievement activities occur during regular school hours.",
            "Students in Junior Achievement programs can ask adults for help if necessary.",
            "The younger that children are, the more they benefit from Junior Achievement programs.",
            "Junior Achievement activities are designed to give students hands-on experience."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Junior Achievement activities are designed to give students hands-on experience."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q17",
          "passageId": "p3",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The photographs in the article help the reader understand the —",
          "options": [
            "reason nylon is superior to cotton for making Velcro",
            "similarity between man-made Velcro and naturally occurring burrs",
            "difficulty Mestral had creating his design for Velcro",
            "reason Mestral thought Velcro would be a useful invention"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "similarity between man-made Velcro and naturally occurring burrs"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q18",
          "passageId": "p3",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "One challenge that Mestral encountered while inventing Velcro was finding —",
          "options": [
            "different uses for Velcro",
            "a country willing to approve a patent for Velcro",
            "a way to make a profit by selling Velcro",
            "a manufacturer that would produce Velcro"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "a manufacturer that would produce Velcro"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q19",
          "passageId": "p3",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The reader can conclude from the details in paragraph 4 that Mestral —",
          "options": [
            "was determined to make his idea for Velcro a reality",
            "did not receive the product rights for Velcro",
            "was denied help because companies had difficulty manufacturing Velcro",
            "wanted Velcro to be known as the world's best fastener"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "was determined to make his idea for Velcro a reality"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q20",
          "passageId": "p3",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "What is the best summary of the article?",
          "options": [
            "Velcro, a fastener named from a combination of the words \"velvet\" and \"crochet,\" was invented by the Swiss engineer George de Mestral. He modeled Velcro after burrs that he found in nature. He learned that nylon was the best material to use to make Velcro.",
            "George de Mestral was an engineer from Switzerland who had a curious mind. After studying burrs stuck to his dog's fur, Mestral decided to create a new kind of fastener. Velcro, the product that Mestral created, is a hook-and-loop fastener that works the same way burrs work in nature.",
            "George de Mestral was the engineer who invented Velcro, a type of hook-and-loop fastener modeled after burrs Mestral found stuck to his dog's fur. Mestral overcame many obstacles as he worked to produce Velcro. Today, Velcro is commonly used to fasten a variety of materials.",
            "A curious man, George de Mestral noticed one day that burrs were stuck to his dog's fur. He looked at these burrs under a microscope and saw that tiny hooks on the burrs allowed them to latch onto the fur. Mestral went on to invent Velcro, which uses hooks similar to those found on the burrs."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "George de Mestral was the engineer who invented Velcro, a type of hook-and-loop fastener modeled after burrs Mestral found stuck to his dog's fur. Mestral overcame many obstacles as he worked to produce Velcro. Today, Velcro is commonly used to fasten a variety of materials."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q21",
          "passageId": "p4",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The photograph after paragraph 3 is included in the selection to —",
          "options": [
            "show the process of how fog turns into water",
            "allow the reader to envision the size of the Namib beetle",
            "help the reader visualize how the Namib beetle collects water",
            "demonstrate how much water is needed by desert insects"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "help the reader visualize how the Namib beetle collects water"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q22",
          "passageId": "p4",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The author focuses on a unique feature of the Namib beetle in order to highlight how the beetle —",
          "options": [
            "could serve as a source of water for desert travelers",
            "struggles to survive in a dry part of the world",
            "uses its wings to stay cool in an arid environment",
            "is able to provide itself with water in the absence of rain"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "is able to provide itself with water in the absence of rain"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q23",
          "passageId": "p4",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "When fog rolls into the desert, the Namib beetle —",
          "options": [
            "releases a waxy substance that covers its back",
            "positions its body in a specific way",
            "creates bumps and troughs on its wings",
            "opens its mouth to drink the water in the air"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "positions its body in a specific way"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q24",
          "passageId": "p4",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The author wrote this selection most likely to —",
          "options": [
            "prove that water can be obtained from moist air",
            "explain how an animal has adapted to living in a hostile environment",
            "show how people can apply designs from nature to create solutions to global problems",
            "emphasize that water is a scarce resource in many areas on Earth"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "show how people can apply designs from nature to create solutions to global problems"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q25",
          "passageId": "p5_paired",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "What is one way that Velcro and the water-collection panels are similar?",
          "options": [
            "The creators of both inventions experimented with different materials.",
            "The inventions were both inspired by the same environment.",
            "The models for both inventions were discovered in unexpected sources.",
            "The inventions received the same amount of support in the beginning."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The models for both inventions were discovered in unexpected sources."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q26",
          "passageId": "p5_paired",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which idea is presented in both the article and the selection?",
          "options": [
            "Simple inventions can provide for basic necessities.",
            "Inventors can find ideas by carefully observing nature.",
            "Selecting the appropriate materials for an invention can be challenging.",
            "Inventions have the greatest chance of success when large companies manufacture them."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Inventors can find ideas by carefully observing nature."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q27",
          "passageId": "p5_paired",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "How did the development of Velcro differ from the development of the water-collection panels?",
          "options": [
            "The water-collection panels took years to create, while Velcro was created in a short period of time.",
            "The water-collection panels are made of synthetic materials, while Velcro is made of natural materials.",
            "The design of the water-collection panels has changed many times, while the design of Velcro has changed very little.",
            "The water-collection panels are intended to solve a specific problem, while Velcro is designed to be applied in many different situations."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The water-collection panels are intended to solve a specific problem, while Velcro is designed to be applied in many different situations."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q28",
          "passageId": "p5_paired",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "What is one outcome of Mestral's invention in \"Natural Inspiration\" that is not shared by the scientists' invention in \"A Brilliant Beetle\"?",
          "options": [
            "Mestral's invention has proved to be financially successful.",
            "Mestral's invention is able to replenish something found in nature.",
            "Mestral's invention can be used to solve more than one problem.",
            "Mestral's invention inspired new uses beyond its original purpose."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Mestral's invention has proved to be financially successful."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q29",
          "passageId": "p5_paired",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "One difference between the Velcro in \"Natural Inspiration\" and the water-collection panels in \"A Brilliant Beetle\" is that —",
          "options": [
            "Velcro is an expensive item to reproduce, whereas the water-collection panels are made from affordable materials",
            "Velcro has been replaced by other inventions, whereas the water-collection panels are still being used",
            "Velcro has become a commonplace item, whereas the water-collection panels are not widely used",
            "Velcro is useful only in the clothing industry, whereas the water-collection panels can be used in many industries"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Velcro has become a commonplace item, whereas the water-collection panels are not widely used"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q30",
          "passageId": "p6",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The description of the setting in lines 8 through 19 highlights a contrast between —",
          "options": [
            "the liveliness of the woods and the steady pace of the river",
            "the simplicity of nature and the complexity of the speaker's emotions",
            "the playfulness of nature and the seriousness of the speaker's purpose",
            "the variety of living organisms around the river and the lack of living organisms in the river"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "the liveliness of the woods and the steady pace of the river"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q31",
          "passageId": "p6",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which sentence best describes the speaker's relationship with the river?",
          "options": [
            "The river forces the speaker to make a decision.",
            "The river reminds the speaker of what is important.",
            "The river introduces the speaker to the outdoors.",
            "The river provides the speaker with an unusual experience."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The river reminds the speaker of what is important."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q32",
          "passageId": "p6",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The poet uses personification in the sixth stanza to show that the river teaches the speaker about —",
          "options": [
            "making good decisions",
            "protecting an important resource",
            "enjoying the experience of living",
            "appreciating the beauty of nature"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "enjoying the experience of living"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q33",
          "passageId": "p6",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The poet placed lines 25 and 26 in their own stanza to —",
          "options": [
            "show that the river affects the speaker's relationships with others",
            "emphasize the speaker's disappointment after spending time at the river",
            "indicate that the speaker goes to the river in search of adventure",
            "highlight the outcome of the speaker's experience while at the river"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "highlight the outcome of the speaker's experience while at the river"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q34",
          "passageId": "p6",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which line from the poem best expresses why the speaker visits the river?",
          "options": [
            "where I like to sit,",
            "whispers excitedly",
            "They help you remember",
            "The trees murmur wisely,"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "They help you remember"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q35",
          "passageId": "p6",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which theme is explored in the poem?",
          "options": [
            "Learning about the patterns of nature can be exciting.",
            "Nature can provide perspective on life.",
            "People should set aside time in their daily schedule to relax.",
            "People who are honest with themselves are better able to appreciate life."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Nature can provide perspective on life."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q36",
          "passageId": "p7",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Read this dictionary entry.\n\nstyle \\'stif(-ə)|\\ n\n1. the fashion of the moment\n2. the type or make of something\n3. a way or manner of behaving\n4. a set of rules for writing\n\nWhich definition best matches the way the word style is used in paragraph 3?",
          "options": [
            "Definition 1",
            "Definition 2",
            "Definition 3",
            "Definition 4"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Definition 3"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q37",
          "passageId": "p7",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Read these sentences from paragraph 3.\n\nI owe much to Paige. Buying a puppy from her meant having the freedom to pick her brain, no matter how often I called—calls that in the beginning were more frequent than she bargained for, I'm sure, and were typically panic-driven.\n\nThese sentences help characterize the author as —",
          "options": [
            "discouraged by his dog's initial behavior",
            "surprised by Paige's vast knowledge of dogs",
            "regretful for taking advantage of Paige's kindness",
            "worried that he wasn't caring for his dog correctly"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "worried that he wasn't caring for his dog correctly"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q38",
          "passageId": "p7",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "What can the reader infer about the woman mentioned in paragraphs 4 through 6?",
          "options": [
            "She is an expert in music in addition to being an expert in dog training.",
            "She disagrees with the author's choice not to provide his dog with formal training.",
            "She thinks the author should be more selective about where he brings his dog.",
            "She is surprised that the author is not interested in learning from her."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "She disagrees with the author's choice not to provide his dog with formal training."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q39",
          "passageId": "p7",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The author presents the information in paragraphs 7 through 13 to illustrate —",
          "options": [
            "why dogs listen only to their owners",
            "what tricks dog owners can easily teach their dogs",
            "why some dogs come to dislike strangers",
            "what some people expect from dogs and dog owners"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "what some people expect from dogs and dog owners"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q40",
          "passageId": "p7",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "Which sentence from the selection best states the author's main objective in raising Atticus?",
          "options": [
            "I know many who tell me that by teaching their dog tricks they worked on their relationship together.",
            "The things I wanted him to learn were basic things that made going through life safe and easy.",
            "Instead he just looked at them, not even bothering to cock his head.",
            "I never saw the point in teaching Atticus tricks."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The things I wanted him to learn were basic things that made going through life safe and easy."
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q41",
          "passageId": "p7",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "The simile in paragraph 16 helps the reader understand that the author —",
          "options": [
            "enjoys finding time to play with Atticus",
            "wants Atticus to grow to be strong",
            "thinks Atticus is a better pet than most dogs",
            "feels responsible for protecting Atticus"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "feels responsible for protecting Atticus"
        },
        {
          "questionId": "q42",
          "passageId": "p7",
          "type": "multiple-choice",
          "question": "What is the best summary of the selection?",
          "options": [
            "The author trusted the advice of Paige Foster, the breeder of his puppy Atticus. After a few months the author had bonded with Atticus, who is so well behaved that he does not need to be leashed or collared.",
            "The author has a peaceful dog named Atticus. People who meet Atticus are surprised that he has not learned any tricks, such as how to put out his paw, because they believe teaching tricks builds the relationship between owner and dog.",
            "The author established a bond with his puppy Atticus by following the dog breeder's advice. Instead of participating in obedience training and teaching his dog tricks, the owner chose to focus on helping Atticus feel safe and happy.",
            "The author had a conversation with a dog expert who was impressed by how well behaved his dog Atticus was. When the expert asked about the kind of training the dog had received, she was surprised to learn that Atticus had not been formally trained."
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The author established a bond with his puppy Atticus by following the dog breeder's advice. Instead of participating in obedience training and teaching his dog tricks, the owner chose to focus on helping Atticus feel safe and happy."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
```
